Mr. TUAN, HUYNH TRAN NGUYEN

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

SUMMARY

Over ten years of testing experience at QA/QC, two of which worked as the core member in several outsourcing project. Team leading skills including working with client and team members on task planning, interpreting project requirements, ensuring timely team deliverables that satisfied client expectations, and leading daily meetings with client. Technical skills including setup and working with CI Tools that integrates with Automation testing tools such as Jenkins, has experience with researching solutions for the difficult technical automation issues. Always welcome a challenge.

CONTACT INFORMATION

Phone: 0908554567

Address: 61/8A Phan Đình Phùng Street, Ward 17, Phú Nhuận District. Email: dsdstimulation@gmail.com

Linkin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gino-tu%E1%BA%A5n-hu%E1%BB%B3nh-160a3b19a

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Project: TIKI Corp –Senior QC Engineer

Duration: May 2021- Now

Responsibilities:

- Building and maintain API Automation Framework which support data synchronous testing.
- Perform API testing and give feedback to Back End developer team.
- Work as QA member of scrum team to perform manual execution based on User Stories from Product Manager.
- Perform database testing on UAT and PRODUCTION to catchup issue when syncing data from the external system.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Chrome.
- Test case tracking: Test Rail. Bug tracking: Jira, Confluence. Testing Tool: PostMan.
- Test Framework: Jest.
- CI/CD: Jenkins.
- Other: SOL, Github.
- Coding Language: Typescript, Javascript.

Project: BE Group JSC – QA Automation Leader

Duration: June 2020- May 2021

Responsibilities:

- Building and maintain API Framework which support API Automation Testing for whole team.
- Deliver core API library to support test data for the other team testing activities.
- Perform API testing and give feedback to Back End developer team.
- Support and mentor team member to get knowledge: technical, business, product, management.
- Provided a solution building a working process: getting assignment, delivering, investigating issue, and adapting request from client.
- Worked as leader of the team: estimating tasks, assigning task to the other members, providing guidance, and making sure those tasks can be done in the acceptable time.
- Solved technical issues, difficult automation issue and people issues with Win-Win solution.

- Take responsibility to make sure the deliveries always meet the estimated time and client expectation.
- Played as a contact point between team members and product: weekly meeting, contact directly with product when discussing about project issue.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Chrome, Android, iOS.
- Test case tracking: Test Rail. Bug tracking: Jira, Confluence.
- Testing Tool: Appium, Selenium, Appium, PostMan. Test Framework: Gauge, Mocha, TestNG.
- CI/CD: Jenkins, GitLabCI.
- Other: SQL, Cloud Services, GitLab, Docker.
- Coding Language: Python, Java, Javascript.

Project: BE Group JSC – QA Manual and Automation Test Engineer

Duration: Sep 2019- June 2020

Responsibilities:

- Develop automation test cases on mobile platform for project be Transport, fin Ops: iOS, Android and web-browser by using Appium for mobile, Taiko Gauge for web app.
- Set up test environment on Android and iOS to run automation project test cases: beTransport, beFood,
- Create and develop check list, test metrics for manual team to perform testing on User Stories.
- Work as QA member of scrum team to perform manual execution based on User Stories.
- Enhance Automation Mobile, API Framework for implementation and execution automation test
- case
- Build e2e ride-hailing scenario for both UI and API testing: iOS, Android.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Chrome, Android, iOS.
- Test case tracking: Test Rail. Bug tracking: Jira, Confluence.
- Testing Tool: Appium, Selenium, Appium, Gauge.
- Coding Language: Python, Java, JavaScript.

Project: Pre Post Sale LogiGear – QA cum Support Engineer

Duration: Mar 2019-Sep 2019

Responsibilities:

- Support external and internal client using Automation test tool.
- Troubleshoot problems for overseas client from Japan, India.
- Execute existing test cases when have release build.
- Contribute to Scrum team as QA staff to test separated functions of product.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Window10, Chrome
- Test case tracking: TFS-MTM.
- Bug tracking: Jira, TFS-MTM.
- Testing Tool: TestArchitect

Project: InContact | LogiGear - Automation Test Engineer

Duration: Mar 2017-Mar 2019

Responsibilities:

- Build automation test cases related to check event information below webpage on Chrome browser.
- Provided a solution building a working process: getting assignment, delivering, investigating issue, and

adapting request from client.

- Solved technical issues, difficult automation issue and people issues with Win-Win solution.
- Build up harness action based on client request by C# language.
- Execute set of test cases to increase stabilization percent of each test modules.
- Build API test cases to test multiple components on inContact webpage.
- Collect and provided all team's daily reports and weekly reports and send out to client.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Window10, Chrome Test case tracking: TFS-MTM. Bug tracking: Jira, TFS-MTM.
- Testing Tool: TestArchitect, C# harness, Selenium Java and C#.

Project: General Mills LogiGear – Automation Test Engineer

Duration: Jan 2017-Mar 2017

Responsibilities:

- Built an automation project to run a set of same TCs on multiple sites on various desktop and mobile browsers (FF, IE, Chrome), mobile (iOS, Android).
- Build automation test cases related to check event information below webpage.
- Provided a solution building a working process: getting assignment, delivering, investigating issue, and adapting request from client.
- Solved technical issues, difficult automation issue and people issues with Win-Win solution.
- Played as a contact point between team members and clients: daily meeting, contact directly with client when discussing about project issue.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Window7, IE, Chrome, Firefox, iOS, Android
- Test case tracking: TFS-MTM.
- Bug tracking: Jira.
- Testing Tool: TestArchitect.

Project: Sperry Non-Insite LogiGear – Automation Test Engineer

Duration: June 2016-Nov 2017

Responsibilities:

- Execute regression process of Non-Insite project and send out regression report to client.
- Set up, install and configure Sperry-Non-Insite-DX application on physical and virtual machines.
- Built automation test cases from TFS-MTM tracking tool.
- Take responsibility to post and verify TA issues for whole Sperry project.
- Acting contact point to rise up TA issues between CE team and Sperry team.
- Solved technical issues, difficult automation issue and people issues with Win-Win solution.
- Provided a solution fixing a difficult TA issues: use python harness, make modification on main action.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Window7, IE, Chrome, Firefox, iOS, Android
- Test case tracking: TFS-MTM.
- Bug tracking: Jira.
- Testing Tool: TestArchitect.

Project: General Mills | LogiGear - Project Lead

Duration: August 2014-June 2016

Responsibilities:

- Built an automation project to run a set of same TCs on multiple sites on various desktop and mobile browsers (FF, IE, Chrome), mobile (iOS, Android).
- Provided a solution building a working process: getting assignment, delivering, investigating issue, and adapting request from client.
- Worked as leader of the team: estimating tasks, assigning task to the other members, providing guidance, and making sure those tasks can be done in the acceptable time.
- Solved technical issues, difficult automation issue and people issues with Win-Win solution.
- Take responsibility to make sure the deliveries always meet the estimated time and client expectation.
- Executed the iteration plan. In case we had any issues that blocked our assignment, contacted client in a timely manner with solutions to get their approvals.
- Played as a contact point between team members and clients: daily meeting, contact directly with client when discussing about project issue.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Window7, IE, Chrome, Firefox, iOS, Android
- Test case tracking: TFS-MTM. Bug tracking: Jira.
- Testing Tool: TestArchitect.

.

Project: Halliburton DecisionSpace Desktop| LogiGear - Automation Test Engineer

Duration: November 2011- August 2014

Responsibilities:

- Built a set of generic and complex high level actions in TA to support the other DSD automation projects. Those actions can be used on many DSD projects that help them save time to set up a new DSD project.
- Played as a core member of the team
- Reported daily status for leader, supported project lead to solve the automation problem, and worked directly with client by email or Lync to discuss a solution or get new assignment.
- Supported team members to solve technical issues (with high complexity), reviewed their actions to make sure they followed ABT and project process.
- Implemented new test modules following ABT and TA best practice. Designed actions that can handle many user cases as possible.
- Guided the new members following team process and automation knowledge. Organized seminars, meetings to introduce, explain, and answer their questions or concerns about the project.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Window7, Linux.
- Test case tracking: None.
- Bug tracking: Jira.
- Testing Tool: TestArchitect.

Project: Kaplan Tutoring | LogiGear - Automation Test Engineer

Duration: October 2010- November 2011

Responsibilities:

- Performed manual testing based on the test cases of Kaplan Tutoring website, and subsequently redesigned and automated those test cases.
- Performed Ad hoc testing on three websites of Kaplan tutoring and reported bug on the website to client using Jira
- Reported directly to leader about tasks, issues, and achievement. Also discussed with leader when encountered any issue related to assignment's progress.
- Finished assigned tasks on time with high efficiency. Sent out daily status report that indicated the tasks, progress, status of assignments and issues if any.

• Ran automated regression and manual regression for a Kaplan Website. Collected results in TA and tracked them in Excel file and send to client at the end of day.

Knowledge:

- Platform: Window XP, MAC OS.
- Test case tracking: None.
- Bug tracking: Jira.
- Testing Tool: Test Architect.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Bachelor of Information Technology: Information Technology, Hoa Sen University, Ho Chi Minh city, Viet Nam

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

SOFT SKILLS

- **OS**: Windows 2008 server, Windows 2003 server/XP/2000, Windows Vista, Windows 7, 10 (5+ years), Android, iOS (2 years)
- **Databases**: SQL Server (setting up, configuration, create SQL query, design database diagram), Oracle Server (set up and configuration)
- Testing Tools:
 - Automation testing tools: QTP, TestArchitect, Selenium, Appium. + CI Tools: Jenkins, Dockers, GitLabCI
 - Programming language: Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript.
 - o Microsoft Office skills: Words, Excel, PPT,...
- Software development processes: Scrum/Agile
- Software project management tool: Jira, Confluences
- Researching new technologies for improving working process by applying them to project.
- Organize the internal training course about basic and advance automation knowledge.
- Represent the new function of automation tools that can help to improve working quality.
- Working with high pressure in project.
- Understand a working process and learn the business flow in the new project quickly
- Be able to analyze, provide a solution to suggest team members overcame the problems.